markertek.com 2019-07-27

# Privacy Policy | Markertek

Tower Products Privacy Notice Effective 3/1/2019

* * *

**Who We Are**

Tower Products Incorporated, herein referred to as Tower, and our affiliated brands headquartered in Saugerties NY, is a highly specialized Broadcast, Pro-AV and Pro-Audio supply house serving the technical side of the entertainment and media industry. We are the controller responsible for the processing of your personal data as a user of this website. The contents of this privacy policy specifically apply to all users of our sites except for EU citizens. If you are an EU citizen, please see our [EU Citizen GDPR Privacy Policy](https://www.markertek.com/gdpr-privacy-policy)

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

**The Information We Collect**

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on our websites. On some pages, you can order products, make requests, and register to receive materials. The types of personal information collected at these pages are:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Phone number
  * Mobile number
  * Job Title
  * Business Type
  * Fax number
  * Credit/Debit Card Information

On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you order a gift online and want it sent directly to the recipient, you will need to submit the recipient's address. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected are:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Phone number
  * Mobile number
  * Fax number

**Our Commitment to Data Security**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**Destruction of Data and Storage Retention**

Tower will store personal data if this is provided for by the legal requirements to which we are subject, maintaining appropriate business and financial records as well as, mandatory data retention laws in the applicable jurisdiction, government orders to preserve data relevant to an investigation, or personal information retained for the purposes of litigation if it were to happen.

**Data Processing with General use of our Websites**

Information about the usage and communication device you are using.

Each time you access our websites, we collect the following information about the device you are using: the IP address, the request from your browser, the platform you’re using (desktop, tablet, mobile device) and the date and time of this request. In addition, the status and the amount of data transferred are recorded as part of this request. We also collect product and version information about the browser used and the operating system of the device, as well as the Internet service provider. We continue to track which website accessed the service.

We process this data so that the content, for example, the website, can be displayed on your device. In addition, we use the data for the operation of the online services and to detect and eliminate errors, to determine the utilization of the websites and to make improvements. The IP address of your device will be stored and then deleted based on mandatory retention policy requirements.

**Create Account**

You can create an account as a user on any of our Websites. To do this you must enter the data requested, for example, name, address and e-mail address. We also record the date and time of registration and the IP address. As part of the registration process, we obtain your consent regarding the use of the data.

The legal basis for processing registration data is to fulfill or initiate a contract with us for the purchase of products. The data will be stored by us for as long as necessary to fulfill the contract. In addition, we store this data for the fulfillment of post-contractual obligations and due to commercial and tax retention periods for the statutory period. This retention period is usually 10 years at the end of the respective calendar year.

**Order Processing Data for Purchases from Tower Websites**

We use your personal data for orders only within our company and affiliated companies to fulfill your order.

When paying by credit card, your necessary data such as name, address, shipping address and the purchase data will be forwarded to the respective credit card company. We will also supply shipping address information to respective shipping companies which will deliver your ordered products. The processing of this personal data is required to fulfill the contract with you.

The data will be stored by us for as long as necessary to fulfill the contract. In addition, we store this data for the fulfillment of post-contractual obligations and due to commercial and tax retention periods for the statutory period. This retention period is usually 10 years at the end of the respective calendar year.

**Subscriptions and Web Forms**

Tower will collect your personal information if you fill out subscription or web form information requests from any of our websites. We will collect name, address, phone, mobile and email address when you subscribe to any of our newsletters, catalog requests, specials and promotional emails, including quote requests.

Tower obtains consent for the processing of your personal data. This data will be stored by us for as long as you are a prospective customer typically for a time of 12 months post customer interaction or as defined in the corporate data retention policy. If you no longer want to receive subscription or product information from us, you can revoke your previous consent at any time and we will discontinue sending Tower subscription information. Simply use the unsubscribe link included in each subscription or send a message to us.

**Store Ratings, Product Ratings and Marketing Emails**

Tower works with Reseller Ratings, Google Customer Reviews and Shopper Approved to rate our products and service. Tower uses Listrak for its email marketing platform. The privacy policies of our affiliated partners are not intended to supersede or govern our policy; however, we suggest you visit their sites to learn more. You may opt-out of any of these at any time.

Google Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
Shopper Approved Privacy Policy: <https://www.shopperapproved.com/privacy.php>  
Reseller Ratings Privacy Policy: <https://www.resellerratings.com/privacy/manage>  
Listrak Privacy Policy: <https://www.listrak.com/privacy-and-terms/privacy.aspx>

**Use of Cookies**

We use cookies. These are small text files stored on your computer containing certain settings and data for sharing with us online about your browser. A cookie usually contains the name of the domain from which the cookie file was sent, as well as information about the age of the cookie and an alphanumeric identifier. Depending on content and storage duration, there are different types of cookies. Most of the cookies we use are so-called "session cookies", which are deleted when you end your browser session. In addition, there are some long-lasting cookies by which we can recognize you as a visitor. Many cookies come directly from us, in addition, the storage and evaluation of individual cookies come from service providers (so-called "third-party cookies").

We inform you about the use of cookies in advance with a corresponding note on a banner.

Some cookies are technically required to enable you to use our online services including checkout. These cookies allow us to collect and store the following data:

  * Language settings
  * Search settings
  * Contents of an online form
  * Information for identifying or authenticating the user
  * Products in the shopping cart

In addition, on our website, we use cookies that allow an analysis of your user behavior, so-called analysis cookies. These cookies allow us to collect and store the following data:

  * Frequency of page views
  * Searches
  * Use of Internet page functions

Cookies allow us to recognize your computer and make any presets available immediately. Cookies help us to improve the online experience and offer you a better and more user-friendly service. The use of cookies is necessary to make the use of our websites easier. Some features can only be offered using cookies. This concerns the search, online forms, customer account, and shopping cart.

We use analysis cookies to improve and optimize the quality of our websites and their content.

The technically necessary cookies we use are so-called session cookies, which are automatically deleted after the end of the browser session. The remaining cookies are stored on your computer. You can delete these saved cookies yourself at any time. Most browsers are also set to automatically accept cookies. However, you can disable the storage of cookies or set your browser to notify you when cookies are sent. Please note that you may be limited or unable to use our online service if you refuse to accept cookies.

To analyze the user behavior for the purposes mentioned above, we use the following programs, which in turn use cookies as explained. The stored data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer needed for the purposes mentioned.

If you are using our Services via a browser you can restrict, block or remove cookies through your web browser settings. The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers also tells you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to delete old cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether.

You can also visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for more information on how to manage and remove cookies across a number of different internet browsers. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve the badge on this website and to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website. Users may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en). In addition, you may view third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt-Out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1). You also have the option to change your choices relating to cookies utilized to deliver behaviorally targeted advertising at our Ad Choices page (Digital Advertising Alliance) or Your Online Choices (European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance).

**Google Analytics**

We use Google Analytics for statistical analysis. Google Analytics is a web analytics service provided by Google LLC., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94034, USA ("Google"). Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies", text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there on behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services related to website activity and Internet usage to the website operator. You can prevent the storage of cookies by using a corresponding setting on your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website fully.

**Retargeting and Remarketing**

Retargeting or remarketing refers to technologies in which users who have previously visited a certain website are shown appropriate advertising even after leaving this website. For this purpose, it is necessary to recognize Internet users beyond their own website, for which purpose cookies of the corresponding service providers are used. In addition, previous usage behavior is considered. For example, if some user views certain products, they may later display these or similar products as advertisements on other websites. It is personalized advertising that is adapted to the needs of each user. It is not necessary for this personalized advertisement to be identified beyond the recognition of the user. The data used for the retargeting or remarketing will therefore not be merged with other data.

We use such technologies to display ads on the Internet. We use third-party providers to deliver such ads. We use, among other things, offers from Google, which allows an automatic display of interesting products for the Internet user. This function is implemented by cookies. Cookies for Google Remarketing and Google AdWords Conversion Tracking can be managed in your browser settings.

**Social Media**

On our websites, you will find links to the social network Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn as well as to our YouTube channels. The links are indicated by the respective logo of the provider.

Clicking on the links opens the corresponding social media pages for which this Privacy Policy does not apply. For details of the applicable provisions, please refer to the respective Privacy Policies of each provider. 

**Facebook Custom Audiences**

Tower Websites use the Facebook Customer's remarketing feature "Custom Audiences" ("Facebook"). This allows users of the website to be shown interest-based advertisements ("Facebook Ads") as part of their visit to the social network Facebook or other websites that also use the process. We are interested in showing you advertisements that are of interest to you to make our online offers more interesting to you.

Due to the marketing tools used, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection to the Facebook server. We have no influence on the extent and further use of the data collected using this tool by Facebook and therefore inform you that according to our knowledge: By integrating Facebook Custom Audiences, Facebook receives the information that you have accessed the corresponding website of our online services or have clicked on an ad from us. If you are registered with a service of Facebook, Facebook can assign the visit to your account. Even if you are not registered with Facebook or have not logged in, there is a chance that the provider will find out and store your IP address and other identifying features.

Disabling the "Facebook Custom Audiences" feature is available to logged-in users at <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_.>

**LinkedIn**

Tower uses LinkedIn Ads and Marketing Solutions. On some occasions, we may also use the Audience Network feature for sponsored content campaigns to deliver our creatives on third-party sites beyond the LinkedIn feed. To manage your LinkedIn advertising preferences, visit: <https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/62931/manage-advertising-preferences>

**Your rights & Correcting Your Information**

You can contact us by phone, e-mail, by mail or web submission form. If you would like to use one of these contact options, we collect the personal data that you provide us with via the selected contact option. This can be your name, address, e-mail address, customer number and telephone number. You can decide for yourself which information you want to give us about the contact options.

We process this data solely for being able to answer or process your inquiry or request. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

As far as you would like to use the contact form in our online offer, we collect the personal data that you provide in the contact form, your name and e-mail address. In addition, we store the IP address as well as the date and time of the request. We process the data transmitted via the contact form exclusively for being able to answer your inquiry or request.

After the matter has been processed by us, the data is first stored in the event of any queries. Deletion of the data can be demanded at any time, otherwise, the deletion takes place after completion of the matter. We will delete the data immediately if we are not obliged to store it due to commercial or tax regulations.

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by contacting us at 845-246-3036. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information.

You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request that credibly shows error. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

**Children’s Policy**

Our Sites are not directed to children under the age of 18. If you are not 18 years or older, do not use our Site. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of 18. If we learn that Personal Data of persons less than 18 years-of-age has been collected through our Site, we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child or a minor under the age of 18 has posted, submitted or otherwise communicated Personal Data to our Site without your consent, then you may alert us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#b9d0d7dfd6f9cdd6cedccbc9d6cedccb97dad6d4) so that we may take appropriate action to remove the minor's Personal Data from our systems.

**Transfer of data to third parties**

In principle, we do not transmit personal data to third parties outside the purposes explained in this Privacy Policy. However, as far as we are obliged by law or by court order, we will forward your data to the authorities entitled to receive information.

**Links to other websites**

Our websites contain links to other websites. These links are usually marked as such. We have no influence on the extent to which the linked websites comply with the applicable data protection regulations. Therefore, we recommend that you also inform yourself as to the respective Privacy Policies of other websites.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Privacy Policy is indicated by the date (below). We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time with future effect. A current version is available directly from any Tower website.   
Status of this Privacy Policy: January 2019
